monicavinader.com 2017-07-16

# Privacy Policy

  * Jewellery
  * Personalise
  * Monica's World

  * Customer Care
  * Contact Us
  * My Account
  * Ordering & Payment 
  * Delivery
  * Exchanges & Returns
  * Our Services
  * Jewellery Care
  * Gift Cards
  * Terms & Conditions 
    * Diamond Giveaway Prize Draw
    * Website Terms of Use
    * Online Terms of Sale
    * Payment Security
    * Privacy Policy
    * Flash and Browser Options

## Privacy Policy

**1 Introduction**  
1.1 This website monicavinader.com (the "Site") is provided and operated by Monica Vinader Ltd ("we", "us" or "our"). We take the privacy of your information very seriously and believe that it is important for you to know what types of information we collect from the Site and how we treat information we may receive from you.

1.2 By using the Site and purchasing any products via the Site ("Product(s)"), you are agreeing to be bound by this privacy policy in respect of the information we collect about you ("Privacy Policy").

1.3 This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with our Website Terms and Terms of Sale (if you purchase any Products).

**2 Personal Information**  
2.1 We may collect and store the following personal information about you:  
(a) certain information required to register with the Site (including title, first and last name, telephone number, email address and delivery and invoice address);  
(b) details of any requests for Products you make through the Site;  
(c) billing information such as your credit card number and expiry date; and  
(d) other information you generate as a result of Site interactions.

**3 Automated Collection**  
We may automatically collect information such as the type of internet browser and operating system you use, the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using, the website from which you linked to our Site and the website you visit as you leave the Site. We use this information to collect broad demographic information about the visitors to the Site and to improve the Site's content and to help us understand how users are interacting with the Site and services provided.

**4 Cookies**  
4.1 When you visit the Site we may store some information (commonly known as a "cookie") on your computer. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your hard drive to store and sometimes track information about you. Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot be accessed by other servers, which means that they cannot be used to track your movements around the web.

4.2 Cookies can be categorised in accordance with the categories found in the ICC UK Cookie guide as set out below:  
(a) strictly necessary cookies - these cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around a website and use its features and enable services you have specifically asked for. Consent is not generally required for these cookies;  
(b) performance cookies - these collect information about how visitors use a website, for example, by recording which pages users go to most often (usually on an anonymous basis);  
(c) functionality cookies - these cookies allow a website to remember the choices a user makes, such as a user name or language preference; and  
(d) targeting or advertising cookies - these collect information about a user's browsing habits and are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator's permission.

4.3 Cookies can also be categorised in accordance with how long they are saved on your device. "Session cookies" are short-term cookies that are only saved on the computer's memory for the duration of a user's visit to the website, whereas "persistent cookies" remain saved in the computer's memory for a set period of time, even after the browser session has ended.

4.4 The following Cookies are set on the Site:

**Cookie Name** | **Purpose** | **Type and duration**  
---|---|---  
Monica Vinader | monicavinader.com uses cookies to enable some of the basic functionality that is required for you to browse and shop on the Site, such as remembering which products you have added to your basket. The information collected through these cookies is only used for this purpose and is never shared or sold on to third parties | Strictly Necessary  
Social Media Plugins | Sites such as Facebook and Pinterest use cookies in order to be able to share and discuss our Products on social networks | Performance cookies  
Session and persistent  
Criteo | These cookies help us to provide you with personalised adverts when you visit other select websites, and help us to understand the effectiveness of those adverts. | Advertising cookies  
Session and Persistent

To opt-out of Criteo:  
<http://info.criteo.com/privacy/cookiecontrol/>  
  
DoubleClick  
Floodlight | DoubleClick uses cookies to serve Monica Vinader display advertisements across third party websites. The DoubleClick cookie serves relevant adverts to potential customers and takes a note whenever someone interacts with an advert. If a customer interacts with an advert and then makes a purchase, a conversion tracking cookie records this and we can then use this information to improve our display adverts | Advertising Cookies  
Persistent  
Google Analytics | These cookies enable Google Analytics software. It helps us take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage and new visitor numbers. That information helps us to improve the Site and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant. The data stored by these cookies never shows personal details from which your individual identity can be established | Performance Cookies  
Session and persistent

To opt-out of Google Analytics:  
<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
  
Kiss Metrics | KISSmetrics uses cookies on our Site for one or more of the following purposes: to help identify unique visitors and/or devices; assess usage patterns and perform traffic analysis; identify visitor preferences; conduct A/B testing; and otherwise administer the KISSmetrics Service. KISSmetrics does not use methods such as browser cache, Flash cookies, or eTags, for acquiring or storing information about end users web browsing activity on client websites or otherwise.

Please be aware that even if you configure your browser settings to reject all cookies, your activity on KISSmetrics client websites will still be recorded by our service, unless you opt out of our service [www.kissmetrics.com/privacy#controls](http://www.kissmetrics.com/privacy#controls "Kiss Metrics Privacy")

| Performance Cookies  
Session and Persistent  
Optimizely | Monica Vinader uses Optimizely cookies to store information about your visit to our Site, helping us understand how our Site is being used. We use this information to show you different content that best fits your needs, as well as allowing us to test what type of content is most popular, thus improving the user experience. All information is anonymous. These cookies do not identify you as an individual | Performance Cookies  
Session and persistent  
Google adwords conversion pixel | This third party cookie shows us how you found our Site and which website you came from. This helps us know which of our online marketing channels is most effective. They also allow us to reward some external websites for directing you to us | Advertising Cookie  
Persistent  
Linkshare | Linkshare use cookies to anonymously record that a user has clicked on a Linkshare link that referred the user to the Site. This information is collected in order to enable us to pay a commission to Linkshare and its affiliates for any sales they may drive on the Site | Advertising Cookie  
Persistent  
  
4.5 You can block or erase cookies from your computer if you want to (your browser's help screen or manual should tell you how to do this), but certain parts of the Site are reliant on the use of cookies to operate correctly and may not work correctly if you set your browser not to accept cookies.

4.6 Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will set cookies when you navigate around the Site. By using our Site you consent to our use of cookies.

**5 Use of Personal Information**  
5.1 Our primary purpose in collecting user information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient and customised experience and to provide the Product(s) you may have requested.

5.2 By using our Site and providing your personal information, you agree that we may use your personal information in order to:  
(a) administer the Site;  
(b) process your order(s), including dispatch, payment and returns (if applicable);  
(c) collect payment for any Products we provide to you;  
(d) make general improvements to our Site and the Products we offer;  
(e) analyse how customers are making use of the Site;  
(f) resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems;  
(g) enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf;  
(h) prevent, detect and investigate potentially prohibited or illegal activities (including fraud and abusive use of the Site), and enforce our Website Terms and Sale Terms; and  
(i) notify you of certain offers and new products (subject to your right to unsubscribe or opt-out).

**6 Sharing Personal Information**  
6.1 Credit or debit card payments will be collected by us. In order for payments to be processed you may need to provide some necessary details to our payment processor. We tell you about this at the point we collect that information on the Site.

6.2 We may also share your personal information with:  
(a) other companies we have instructed to provide services or goods for us;  
(b) law enforcement agencies, other governmental agencies or third parties if we are required by law to do so; and  
(c) other business entities should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity, or if we undergo a re-organisation with that entity.

6.3 Except as expressly set out in this Privacy Policy, our Website Terms or our Terms of Sale, we will not disclose any of your personal information without your permission.

**7 Links to and from other websites**  
7.1 We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites even if you access them using links from our Site and we recommend that you check the policy of each website you visit and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.

7.2 In addition, if you linked to this Site from a third party website, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners or operators of that third party website and recommend that you check the policy of that third party website and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.

7.3 You are not entitled (nor will you assist others) to set up links from your own website(s) to the Site (whether by hypertext linking, deep-linking, framing, toggling or otherwise) without our prior written consent, which we may grant or withhold at our absolute discretion.

**8 Security and Storage of Personal Information**  
8.1 Although we maintain safeguards to protect your personal information from unauthorised or inappropriate access, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to us or provided through the Site.

8.2 As part of our service of providing Products to you through the Site, the information you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside of the European Union ("EU"). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU or one of our service providers is located in a country outside of the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the UK. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

8.3 If you use the Site while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU.

**9 Opt-Out**  
Where we use your personal information for mailing purposes, you will have the right to unsubscribe at any time. To unsubscribe just click on the unsubscribe link of any marketing email that you receive from us. If you have an online account you can opt out on the My Details page.

**10 Contacting Us**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by clicking here.

**11 Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
11.1 We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on the Site. All amended terms will automatically take effect immediately on posting. Please check this Privacy Policy periodically to inform yourself of any changes. In continuing to use the Site you confirm that you accept the then current terms and conditions in full at the time you use the Site.
